

tejbirwason@gmail.com | H: 7788834175 | Montreal, QC

Summary

Pragmatic software engineer with four years of professional experience shipping real products to real customers. Past employers have described me as an eager and quick learner, friendly, conscientious, and a strong communicator.

Skills

- Full-Stack Web Development
- Javascript (Angular, React, Node.js)
- Python
- Ruby/Rails

- Product Design
- Data Visualization
- API Design
- Swift Mobile Development

Experience

Up N' Go | San Diego, CA Full-Stack Developer (Remote) 02/2019 - Current

SAP | Vancouver, BC Software Developer 07/2016 - 11/2018

Amazon | Seattle, WA Software Development Engineer Intern 01/2015 - 05/2015

Alcatel-Lucent | Ottawa, ON Software Engineer Intern 05/2014 - 08/2014

Broadcom | Richmond, BC Software Engineer Intern 05/2013 - 12/2013

- Part of the early engineering team co-leading the design and development of the core product and payment integration infrastructure (Apple Pay, Venmo, Google Pay)
- Improved page load times by 200% by transitioning legacy features to a Redux datastore and React front-end
- Led the design, implementation, deployment and testing of 18 high-visibilty complex data visualization features used by thousands of SAP entreprise customers including RedBull, UnderArmor
- Pioneered the development of an A/B testing framework to perform end-to-end inventory movement simulations during peak shopping season. Reduced test creation time from 2 hours to 1 minute
- Optimized DynamoDB data stores to load-balance the enormous data generated during simulations
- Reduced equipment quote creation time from 3 days to 2 hours
- Built a stand-alone web app that abstracted away complex business logic that calculates equipment deployment cost. Today a majority of Alcatel's €14.4 billion revenue flows through this quotation tool
- Reduced development time by 70% using debug API commands to stress-test android devices enabled with Broadcom chips
- Built extensive Python test suites in collaboration with chip designers

Education

The University of British Columbia | Vancouver, BC Bachelor of Applied Science in Computer Engineering (Software) - With Distinction 05/2016